Mohammed Bilal ANSARI

Machine Learning Engineer

m www.linkedin.com/in/mohammedbilalansari/

• https://github.com/bilalsp

♠ 35 Rue Roche Genès, 63170 Aubière, France♦ (+33) 6 29 89 20 30

mohammedbilalansari.official@gmail.com

https://bilalsp.github.io

SUMMARY

Curious, self-motivated, and enthusiastic data science graduate with 1+ years of work experience in machine learning and statistical analysis. Ability to solve the complex problem and work on different technologies. Adaptive data science major eager to join innovative organization.

EDUCATION

2019 - 2021 Double Degree Master's in "Data Science and International of Computer

Science"

University of Clermont Auvergne, Clermont-Ferrand, France

National Research University Higher School of Economics, Moscow, Russia

2014 - 2018 Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science (BAC+4)

Vel Tech Rangarajan Dr. Sagunthala R&D Institute of Science and

Technology, Chennai, India

EXPERIENCE

Machine Learning Intern

Mar 2021 - Aug 2021

LIMOS, Clermont-Ferrand, France

 Proposed and implemented a solution for Machine Scheduling Problem (NP-Hard optimization problem) in the fabric industry using deep reinforcement learning

- Gain experience to train a model on High-Performance Computing (HPC) cluster
- Designed and implemented exhaustive and random search solvers for model performance comparison
- Implemented custom model, layers, and training loop using low-level APIs of TensorFlow

Machine Learning Engineer

Jul 2018 - Jul 2019

Robert Bosch GmbH, Bangalore, India

- Reduced the operational cost of the software testing project by around 16% by building and deploying deep learning based natural language processing (NLP) model for detecting duplicate testcases and clustering semantic testcases on AWS cloud using docker container
- Wrote high quality modular code for production and packaged for deployment
- Developed and maintained Power BI reports and dashboards from multiple data sources using data blending
- Built and maintained SQL scripts to extract the data from healthcare database of Philips Innovation Center
- Explored, cleaned, and manipulated the raw data to get insight and feed into machine learning model starting from business problem
- Performed data visualization to uncover the insight and prepared the data for downstream prediction model
- Extensively involved in interacting with the client to collect the various project requirements

Research Fellow

Jan 2018 – Apr 2018

Tamkang University, Taipei, Taiwan

- Developed and proposed improved emotion-driven music system architecture based on the Support Vector Machine (SVM) algorithm with an accuracy of 89.04%
- Implemented several machine learning models from research papers to reproduce the result
- Reported weekly progress to supervisor and presented final result to Head of the Department

Projects

Some of the academic and personal projects which I worked on recently. Available at https://bilalsp.github.io#projects with code repository.

DETAILS

Date of Birth: 21.03.1996 Nationality: Indian

SKILLS

Programming Languages

- Python
- C/C++

Framework and libraries

- Pandas & NumPy
- Scikit-learn
- Matplotlib
- Seaborn & Plotly
- Keras & TensorFlow
- Flask
- Apache Spark

Cloud and Miscellaneous Technologies

- AWS and Azure Cloud
- Power BI
- SQL
- Docker
- Git
- REST API
- Hypothesis Testing

Certifications

- Deep Learning Specialization by deeplearning.ai and offered through Coursera
- Natural Language
 Processing by HSE and offered through Coursera
- Applied AI with Deep Learning by IBM and offered through Coursera
- Cluster Analysis in Data Mining by University of Illinois and offered through Coursera
- SQL for Data Analytics by Start-Tech Academy and offered through Udemy

Languages

- English (Fluent)
- Hindi (Native)
- French (Basic)